当人们发现你是医生的时候  总会出现这样的情况
there's this thing that happens when people find out you're a doctor.
早上好
Good morning.
你有没有... 提过...
DiD... you... patter?
求婚?
Propose?
还没有
No, not yet.
到时候我一定第一个通知你
you'll bethe first to know.
他们不再把你当作凡夫俗子  而视你如万物之神
They stop seeing you as a person and begin to see you  as something  bigger than you are.
她怎么样了?
How's she doing?
还行
She's, uh... okay.
还可以
She's okay.
人们一定要把我们奉作神仙
They have to see us that way, as gods.
不然的话  我们也只是一群乌合之众
Otherwise we're just like  everyone else--
缺乏信心  不甚完美  平淡无奇
unsure... flawed... normal.
她怎样?
How's she doing?
-没什么变化  这是大脑动脉超声检查?  -对
- There's no change. Is this the M. C. A. Doppler? - Yeah.
要给你带点什么吗?  咖啡?
Can I get you anything, coffee?
不用了  谢谢
I'm fine. Thanks.
所以我们故作坚强  假扮清高
So we act strong, we remain stoic.
我们企图隐藏自己也是茫茫众生这一事实
We hide the fact that we're all too human.
他还在打肿脸充胖子?
He still beating himself up?
艾迪森觉得他还在硬撑
Addison thinks he's still beating himself up.
阿历克斯
Alex...
神经科的老大已经与他的病人守望相依三天了
the head of neuro hasn't left his patient's bedside for three days.
他还好啦  我以为艾迪森要走了呢
He's fine. And I thought Addison was leaving.
她昨天晚上把她弟弟送上了飞机
She put her brother on a plane last night.
承认吧
Admit it.
她整天在你男人面前晃来晃去  挺烦人的
Her hanging around your guy... it bugs.
没有  你才讨人厌呢
It doesn't bug. You bug.
克莱夫  呼叫艾迪森  跟她说我要她留下来
karev. Page Addison. Tell her I need her to stay.
好吧  有点烦人
Okay. It bugs a little.
流过血管的血液稀少造成了轻微的中风和失语症
The lack of blood flow through the vessel is causing the mini-strokes and aphasia.
手术不能再拖了
We can't put the surgery off any longer,
我要做的是修复  叫做颅内外动脉搭桥
so what I'm gonna do is a repair that's called an e. C. /I. C. Bypass.
这能治好中风?  手术过后她会好?
And--and that will fix the strokes?She'll be better after this?
希望如此
I'm hoping it will work, yes.
但是
but... the...
我相信对孩子不安全的话他们是不会这么做的
I'm sure they wouldn't operate unless itwere safe for the baby
是不是  蒙特玛丽医生?
Right, Dr. Montgomery?
你的血压还比较高
Oh, your--your blood pressure is still high,
这就是为什么我会在手术现场监控你和孩子
but that's why I'll be there, to monitor both you and the baby.
好好休息  回见
Get some rest. We'll see you soon.
谢谢你留下来
Thank you for staying.
我也只有这么做才能报答你对阿切的救命之恩
It's the least I could do for you saving archie.
我知道我们已经讨论过关于孩子的事了
I know we said before, about the baby
但如果真出了什么状况
But if something should happen
如果真到了生死抉择的时候  救我的妻子
if it comes down to a choice, save my wife.
孩子还可以再生  而她的生命就不能挽回了
We can make another baby. We can't make another her.
男性  52岁  摔下楼梯
52-year-old male, fell down a flight of stairs.
胆囊切除术后五天  好像正是摔跤的原因
He's five days post-op from a cholecystectomy, which looks to have caused the fall.
为什么没了胆囊会摔跤?
Why would having your gall bladder removed cause a fall?
非腹腔镜胆囊切除?
a non-laparoscopic choli?
先生  你在哪个医院做的手术?
Sir, what hospital did you have your operation at?
这里
Here.
我的医生是坎贝尔医生
Uh, my surgeon was Dr. Campbell.
真相大白
That explains it.
-失陪以下  -好的
- Excuse us for a moment. - Okay.
怎么了?
all right, what?
坎贝尔是西雅图格蕾斯医院第一位女性外科医生
Campbell was seattle grace's first female surgeon
尽管是先锋人物
as pioneer as it gets.
大部分时间她只是坐在办公室里  名扬天下
Mostly she just sits in her office and spreads prestige around.
偶尔她也会做做循例手术
she...  still does routine surgery now and then.
你是说她笨手笨脚地搞砸了循例手术?
You mean botches routine surgery.
我来呼叫主任
I'll page the chief.
不  呼叫坎贝尔  这是她的病人
No, page Campbell. It's her patient.
让她再手刃病人一次?
And let her maim the guy again?
为什么不呼叫一个真正懂得手术的人  而去麻烦一个
How about we page someone who actually knows how to operate instead of some dinosaur
死拽着手术刀  不愿意去颐享天年的老顽固?
who refuses to retire her scalpel and go join her friends in boca?
老顽固驾到
the dinosaur is here.
不用呼叫我了
No need to page me.
你去探过她的口风没?
So did you scope her out yet?
-谁?  -亚利桑那
- Who?- Arizona.
哦  那个  我还没时间到儿科那转悠
Oh, right, that. No, I haven't had a chance to swing by peds
让护士指认
and ask the nurse to point out the attending
那个在酒吧肮脏的卫生间里亲吻了我朋友的主治医生
who kissed my friend in a dirty bar bathroom.
至少你还有时间喝咖啡
Well, at least you're still good for coffee.
那不是给你的
Oh, that's not for you.
咖啡?  谢谢你  马克
Coffee?Why, thank you, mark.
也不是给你的
Well, it's, uh, that's not for you, either.
早上好  格蕾医生
morning, Dr. Grey.
你自个留着吧
Yeah, you can keep your secret coffee.
你没告诉德里克之前
Until you tell Derrick, our relationship is gonna continue to consist
我们都要偷偷摸摸的
of you hiding in the attic
你藏在阁楼里  而我拿着零食闪过梅丽狄斯的卧室
and me smuggling snacks past mer's bedom.
你知道这样然你看起来像什么吗?
Do you know what that makes you?
-你的男朋友?  -是啊  安妮·法兰克
- Your boyfriend?- Yeah. Anne frank.
我在跟安妮·法兰克约会
I am dating anne frank.
我已经厌倦了
And I'm tired of it.
我想和你一起下楼梯
I-I want to go downstairs with you.
我要让德国人去吃屎
I want to tell the germans to kiss my ass.
过不了多久我就要告诉他
I'm gonna tell him soon.
那时  你就将是我参加他们婚宴的女伴
And when I do, you'll be my date to the wedding.
-德里克求婚了?  -还没有  我是说他有所行动的时候
- Derek proposed? - Well, not yet, but when he does.
这项申请是开始新生活的第一步
This application is the first step in the start of a new life.
感觉如何?
How are we feelin'?
信心满满?  勇往直前?
Positive?Confident?
我很好  非常好
I am good. Great.
你管好自己就好了
Uh, you take care of your own feelings.
儿科手术的竞争非常激烈
Peds surgery is super competitive.
这就是为什么我搞了这么多推荐信  它们会让竞争不值一提
That's why I've come armed with letters of recommendation that'll put the competition to shame.
听听  谢博德夸我才干过人  足智多谋
Look, Shebold says I'm talented and resourceful,
斯隆觉得每日与我共事是一种荣幸
sloan finds it an honor to work with me every day, and I--
院长呢?  院长怎么说?
what about the chief? What'd the chief think?
我还在弄呢
I'm still working on that.
贝利  只有院长说了才算啊
Bailey, the chief's is the only recommendation that matters.
选拔委员会的每一个人都对他俯首称臣
Everyone on the selection committee works for him.
我知道啊  你冷静点
I know. You calm down.
我一切尽在掌握之中
I've got it under control.
好极了  就我个人来说
Good, cause speaking on behalf of me
我是很希望你加入的
We couldn't be more excited to have you.
院长  友情提示
Ch--uh, chief. Just a friendly nudge.
你的推荐信今天结束之前要给我
Your letter of recommendation is due by the end of the day.
我会提醒帕特里夏
I'll remind patricia.
你写了?
You have written it?
反正不会少了你的
You'll get your letter of recommendation.
-我需要更多的时间  -没门
- I need more time. - No.
别误会
Don't get me wrong
我很高兴您选择了我
I am honored that you asked me
而不是其他住院医生
over all the other residents,
但是 你知道
but, you know
要在500字以内概括您这样一位医生不容易
It's not easy distilling a doctor of your stature down to 500 words or less.
我选择你  欧麦利
I chose you, o'malley
因为你是唯一我相信不把这事搞砸的人
Because you were the only one I could trust to do this without screwing it up
不准搞砸!
So don't.
让他上... 甘... 奇
Make he sure he planes the patio.
-港... 金  -我会让他上钢琴课的
- Plates the... - we'll get him piano lessons, yes.
刚里... 宫里
Only puddle shell... uh... only public s--
上公立学校
public school
我知道  到时候他就不会变成个势利眼
So he doesn't become a snob, I know.
但我没必要担心这一切
But I don't have to
因为你会一路护航保驾
Because you're gonna be there
确保我没把他教成个怪人
To make sure I don't turn him into a jerk.
我们到了
We're here.
-我爱...  -我知道  你爱我
- I love just... - I know. You love me.
我也爱你
and I love you.
过会见
I'll see you in a few.
谢谢你
thank you.
她的血压比昨天高
Hey, her blood pressure's up a little higher than it was yesterday.
我们等不了了
We can't wait.
-我知道  我只是  -你想让我提高警惕  我了解
- Well, I know, but I just - You want me to be aware. I understand.
你是个好医生  我也是
You're a good doctor. So am I.
让我们一起救死扶伤吧
Let's just be good together.
你我的相好相处得不错
Your guy and my guy work well together.
我男人跟谁合作都很好
Well, my guy works well with everyone.
-斯蒂文斯医生  -什么事?
- Dr. Stevens. - Yes.
你觉得我们今天有可能参加手术么?
Do you think we'll get to scrub in on a surgery today?
你们这帮笨瓜真的认为自己可以为别人的生命负责?
You losers really think you're capable of holding someone's life in your hands
而你们却连"实习生超级碗"(外科技术的竞赛)都搞不定?
when you could barely finish the intern bowl?
是吗?  拜托
Really? Come on.
斯蒂文斯医生
Dr. Stevens.
-还记得我么?  -怎么了?
- Remember me? - Yes.
我几天前来过这里
I was here a couple of days ago
你告诉我我有可能得了癌症
And you told me I might have cancer.
你把我转给了肿瘤学家
Yeah, and you sent me to an oncologist
然后那家伙又把我送到了免疫学家那
Who sent me to an immunologist
然后我就在形形色色
who then sent me to some other kind of "ologist"
在我踏进这个陷阱之前闻所未闻的专家之间转来转去
that i had never even heard of before I set foot in this death trap.
在花了八万块用于各种医疗测试之后
And $80, 000 in medical tests later
我得知我唯一的毛病就是贫血
The only thing wrong with me is that I'm anemic.
贫血?
Anemic?
我的律师认为
my lawyer seems to think
这里有人标错了血液
that someone here mislabel the blood
和别人的搞错了
switched it with someone else's.
我被告知不要到这来
And I was told not to come here
但是我的良心还是让我来告诉你
But my conscience wanted to make sure
你要仔细检查那天来看病的所有人的档案
that you went through those files of everybody who was here at the clinic that day.
当然
Of course.
我们会的  非常抱歉
Of course we will. I'm so sorry.
别跟我道歉
Well, don't apologize to me.
我只是有小小的贫血
I'm just anemic.
你跟那个濒死的人去讲
You apologize to that dying person.
那是大脑中动脉?
is that the middle cerebral artery?
是的  等我接好颞浅动脉就能缝合了
Yes, after I connect the S. T. A. , We will be able to close.
婴儿自发性心率减缓
the baby's having spontaneous decels.
母亲低血压
Mom's hypotensive.
德里克  我不知道他们还能撑多久
Derek, I don't know how much more they can handle.
大脑中动脉有些出血
The M. C. A. Is bleeding a bit.
情况不大好  请缝合
It shouldn't be contributing. Sutures please.
血压下降
Pressure's dropping.
德里克  孩子得出来了
Derek, the baby's gonna need to come out.
我快好了  艾迪森  耐心点
I'm almost done, Addison. Just wait.
不是我不耐心
It's not me that can't wait.
心率减缓越来越严重了
the decels are getting more frequent.
24周大的胎儿根本承受不了这一切  四天内三场手术
A 24-week-old fetus can't handle this-- three surgeries in four days.
孩子一定要出生  德里克
We have to get the baby out, Dirlik.
但这孩子还太小了
The baby is too young to come out.
最近一次的心率减缓持续了整整30秒
Last decel lasted a full 30 secos.
好吧  克莱夫  我们开始
All right, that's it. Karev, let's go.
接生吧
I'm taking him out.
-结束缝合  -10号手术刀
- Cut the suture. - 10-blade.
留着孩子
Leave the baby in.
我完成了
Done
好了
你只是小骨折  所以不需要手术
You've got a minor fracture, so you won't need surgery.
你应该不久就能下地走路了
You should be on your feet within a few weeks.
我都不知道自己在想些什么
I don't know what I was thinking.
我知道伤口愈合得并不像我想象的那么快
I knew the wound wasn't healing as fast as I had hoped, but--
下一次再这样要打电话给我  约翰
next time, you call me, john.
杨医生
Dr. Yang
跟我的病人说说
Explain to my patient
你觉得我应该怎么做
What you feel I should've done differently in order
来避免这样的并发症
to avoid this complication.
别害羞  杨医生
Now don't be shy, Dr. Yang.
好的
Okay.
病人在微创手术之后
Well, patient's status post minimally invasive procedures
术后后遗症和恢复时间都会减少
have been shown to have decreased post-surgical discomfort and recovery times.
说人话  杨医生
In human, please, Dr. Yang.
这个手术应该用腹腔镜来做
This surgery should've been done laparscopically.
亨特医生
Dr. Hunt
也许你可以跟杨医生解释一下
Perhaps you can explain to Dr. Yang
我为什么要这么做手术?
Why I chose to do the surgery this way?
尽管有些医生喜欢使用新的技术
Although some doctors prefer to use the new technology,
但也有医生认为这种方式实际上更加危险因为
there are others who believe it's actually more risky since we can't see
因为在手术过程中我们不能移动  视野有限
or move around as much during the surgery.
其实两种都半斤八两
It's half a dozen either way.
说得好  亨特医生
Bravo, Dr. Hunt.
你明白吗?  约翰
do you understand, john?
明白
YeS.
我相信你做出了正确的判断  坎贝尔医生
I have no doubt you did the right thing by me, Dr. Campbell.
好极了
Wonderful!
杨医生
Now, Dr. Yang
请带我们的病人去做CT
Please take our patient to C. T.
相信在我和亨特医生协商治疗方案的过程中
Maybe you'll learn something in the process
你会有所收获的
while I confer with Dr. Hunt about our course of treatment.
我在赶时间  斯蒂文斯
I'm on a deadline, stevens.
赛迪·哈里斯标错了病人的血液样本
Sadie harris mislabeled a patient's blood sample
诊所可能要吃官司
And now the clinic is probably getting sued.
谢天谢地赛迪·哈里斯不再干了
It's a good thing sadie harris no longer works here then.
好什么  不只她受牵连
No, it's not. It's not a good thing because it isn't just her.
这帮子实习生都有可能犯这样的错
The intes, all of them, they are capable of the same mistake.
-他们危险而又可恶  -斯蒂文斯
- They are dangerous and they are bad. - Stevens--
别跟我说我过于感情用事
Don't tell me I am overly emotional
什么工作中不应带入私人情感
And that it isn't personal
我就是看他们不爽
Because it is personal
我这么努力教育他们
I have worked so hard to teach them, and...
没错  我针对他们
And it is personal.
斯蒂文斯
Stevens
你不知道你们第一年来时
You don't think I thought the same thing
我也这么想么?
about you people every day for the first year you are too?
你知道主任跟我说什么吗?
You know what the chief told me when I did?
滚蛋
Get out.
你是不是没休息好  谢博德医生?
You don't get much rest, do you, Dr. Shepherd?
你听见自己刚刚说什么了吗?
did you hear yourself just then?
天哪
Oh, my god. oh, my god.
我  我能说话了
I can-- I can talk.
是呀  听听
I know! Listen to you.
孩子呢?
And the baby?
孩子怎么样?
How is the baby?
孩子的情况很稳定
Yeah The baby's stable
但是  你的新的化验报告显示你有子痫
However, um, your new labs show that you're preeclamptic.
我们本希望制止它恶化到当前这个阶段
Now we had hoped to keep it from progressing to this stage,
但是手术对你的身体来说是个很大的负荷
but the stress of the surgery, it was a lot on your body.
所以  我  我们需要担心吗?
So do we--do we need to be worried?
拜托  谢博德医生
come on, Dr. Shepherd.
请告诉我们担忧的日子已经结束了
Please tell me we're done being worried.
这是一星期以来他们唯一一次感到有希望的时候
That is the first moment of hope they've had in a week.
子痫可不是闹着玩的  他们一定要知道
Preeclampsia is serious. They needed to know.
你对这个病人太过投入了
You are too close to this patient.
别在这点上抓着不放
Stop fighting me on this.
我们的手术成功了
We had a victory in there.
这点值得高兴
Let's stay focused on that.
我们向患者家庭如实以告
We give the family all of the information.
这就是我们的职责  德里克
That's our job, Dirlik.
看样子这回和我的那位占了上风
Looks like my guy won that round.
梅丽狄斯
Meredith
克莱夫  你能不能去取一下詹的
Uh, karev, can you go get jen's
血液检测结果?
Blood test results?
给我一个不告诉主任的理由
Give me one reason why I shouldn't go to the chief.
为什么?  因为手术成功了啊
Why?The surgery was a success.
他第一次手术犯了错
He made a mistake in her first surgery
导致一系列并发症
He caused a series of complications
所以很内疚
He feels responsible
告诉我我为什么不用担心
So tell me why I should worry less.
为什么我不用去找主任
Tell me why I shouldn't go to the chief.
门诊时
During the clinical trial
他失去很多病人 这影响到他
he lost a lot of patients, and it affected him
我觉得是件好事
For the better I think.
他现在尽可能仔细了
He cares more, if that's possible.
你得相信他
You just have to trust him.
好吧
Okay.
卡里欧琵
Calliope.
一直没见到你啊
I haven't seen you around.
是啊  我一直在回避你
Yeah, well, I've been avoiding you.
我知道  觉得有点尴尬
I know. It's--it's so weird.
你吻了一个从没见过的女人
You share a kiss with a woman you've never seen before...
老实说这是新冒险之旅
Honestly, this is a new adventure.
我已经准备好来第二次了...
One I'm so ready to take for the second time and...
无论如何
Anyway...
你想跟我约会吗
do you want to go on a date with me?
等等  艾瑞卡和你... 她是你第一个?
Wait. Uh, Erica and you-- she was your first?
是啊
Yeah.
那我想我的答案是不
Okay, so then I guess my answer is... no.
-抱歉  -等等
- I'm sorry. - Wait. Wait, wait.
什么?  是你在洗手间里
What? Uh... um... you kissed me...
不知何故地先吻了我
out of no where, in a bathroom.
看到没  这就是我想要避免的
Okay, see, this is what I try to avoid.
你正处于探索和试验阶段
You're all exploring and experimenting and... yay.
对你来说现在这样很兴奋
This is a really exciting time for you.
但我在儿科工作
But I work in peds.
一整天都和新生儿在一起
I spend my entire day around newborns.
所以我的生活里不需要新手了
So i-I try not to in my personal life.
谢谢你的请求
Thanks for asking, though.
我真是不胜荣幸
I'm super flattered.
不胜荣幸
Super.
他  还有他
his... and his.
我没改变心意
I-- as discussed.
谢谢
Thank you.
新手
newborn.
我可不是新手
I'm not a newborn.
我是个... 我是个高级住院医生
I'm a--i'm a senior resident.
我是个很棒的外科医生
I'm a great surgeon.
我都离过一次婚了  对吧
I'm a--I'm a divorc for god sake, right?
我... 我是来找你取得一点赞同的  贝利
I'M... I'm, uh, looking for you to agree with me here, bailey.
贝利?
Bailey?
主任  他给我写了封正式的推荐信
The chief, he... he wrote me a form letter of recommendation.
什么?  不可能吧  就凭你俩的关系
What? That's insane. He's the chief and you're Bailey.
手术技能精湛  深受护士的爱戴
"Pleasant in the O. R. and enjoyed by the nurses.
她做了许多研究
She has completed aserviceable amount of research.
可良好地各个部门的工作  良好
... A fine addition to any program.   Fine.
他用了良好这个词
He used the word "fine"
还不如不写任何东西呢
a blank page would mean more.
我成功完成了一个12人的连环手术
I pulled off a 12-person domino surgery.
我为一个垂死的女孩换了留个器官
I took out and put back six of a dying girl's organs.
我可是贝利医生啊
I am Dr. bailey.
我绝对不知是良好而已
I am better than fine.
至少他没称你为新手
well, at least he didn't call you a baby.
还有一分钟  特兹安先生
just a minute more, mr. Terzian.
伺候好她了吗
oh, done tending to her highness?
你知道吗  你对人很刻薄
You know, you're tough on people.
高标准严要求是好事  但这是医学
It's good to hold such high standards, but this is medicine.
没有人是完美的
No one's perfect.
她又固执又神圣不可侵犯
She's stubborn and out of touch.
那她四十年的经验呢?
So her 40 years of experience means nothing?
如果没合理利用等于白费
Well, no, uh, not if you don't use them correctly.
她不是想凭她的经验来做手术吗
Now she wants to be old and keep operating?
好啊  多去关注医学的最新进展吧
Fine. Just keep up with the medicine.
克里斯提娜  这只是一个病例罢了
Cristina, this is one case.
你不能凭一个病例就一棍子打死她
You can't judge someone based on one case.
病人有权知道医生是何种人
That patient deserves to know who his doctor is
不管她会不会被伤害
No matter whose feelings it happens to hurt.
无论如何  我们都不能犯那样的错误
laparoscopic or open, none of us should've made that mistake.
杨医生  你清楚告发的是
Doctor Yang, you realize that you're charging one of our hospital's
医院最受尊敬的外科医生吗
Most respected surgeons with negligence?
清楚  主任
Yes, sir.
亨特医生  你也认同杨医生的评估?
Dr. Hunt, do you agree with Dr. Yang's assessment?
这是杨医生的要求
This is Dr. Yang's call.
我在问你  亨特医生
I'm asking you, Dr. Hunt.
坎贝尔级别比我高  主任
Campbell outranks me, sir.
我觉得您直接去找她谈会比较好
Uh, I think it would be best for you to discuss it with her directly.
没错  杨医生  帮我呼叫坎贝尔医生
Very well. Dr. Yang, page Dr. Campbell.
告诉她手术前我想跟病人谈谈
Tell her I want to speak to that patient before the surgery.
知道了  主任
Yes, sir.
你算保持中立咯
Way to take a stand.
在这儿呢  我的传奇大师
There he is-- the legend himself.
你怎么样  传奇?
How are you, legend?
我很好 你喝醉了吗  我需要担心你吗
I'm fine, are you drunk? Should I be worried about you?
他又重新找回了幽默感
And he's got his sense of humor back.
是啊  你的病人怎样了?
- Yeah.  - How's your patient?
她很好
She's good.
情况稳定
Stable.
今天是这么久以来
This today's the first day in a long time
我第一次觉得自己工作很出色
that I remember what it feels like to be good at my job.
你?  拜托
You? Come on.
你可是医学界的达赖喇嘛
You're like the dalai lama of surgery.
全世界的人都来
People from all over the world come here
要你为他们开脑  还有呢?
To let you cut into 'em, and you know what else?
你的工作的确很出色
You look good doing it.
顺便说句  我喜欢你的胡子
I like the facial hair, by the way.
不长不短  刚刚好
Keep it that length--no more, no less.
好了好了  别说了
Okay, okay, all right, stop.
德里克  有些事我们得谈谈
Derek, there's something that we need to discuss.
去吧  去和艾迪森上床吧
Go ahead and have sex with Addison.
- 艾迪森?  什么意思?  不是啦 - 去吧
- Addison? What? No.  - Go for it.
我不想跟艾迪森上床
I don't want to have sex with Addison.
真的?
Really?
那你想谈什么?
Well, what did you want to discuss?
没什么
Nothing.
好吧
Okay.
看到我妈怎样了?
How's my mother?
尖酸  火爆
Bitter, angry.
天才
Genius.
知道哪儿有问题吗
Know what's so wrong?
主任和你妈吵得这么凶
Is how much the chief and your mother fought
他们做爱肯定很激烈
The sex must've been great.
你说这是有问题
Okay, you saying that-- that's wrong.
什么问题?  整个医疗卫生体系?
What's wrong? Our entire health care system?
- 我很同意这点 - 等等  看这段
- 'Cause I agree.  - Wait, here it is.
1979年3月3日
"March 3, 1979"
协助马格利特 坎贝尔做脾脏切除术
Assisted Margaret Campbell on a splenectomy.
这履历拽吧?
Impressive resume?
高超的技术  看到吧?  那时候就如此了
adequate technique. " See? Hack. Even then.
你跟着马格利特 坎贝尔一起工作?
You're working with Margaret Campbell?
是啊  老家伙们觉得她还能做手术
Yeah. Ye oldie timey thinks she's still ane enough to keep doing surgeries.
所以我喜欢你妈
See, that's what I like about your mom.
她患了阿兹海默后就不出山了
She wasn't all alzheimery and still operating.
如果我给人治病犯了错而且还自以为是地
Do me a favor and shoot me if I start making mistakes
继续错下去的话麻烦你杀掉我吧
on patients and still think it's kosher to keep cutting.
口气像谢博德
Sounds like Shepherd.
艾历克斯  拜托
Alex--please.
我老板是对的  你男人搞破了动脉瘤
My guy is right. Your guy nicked an aneurysm
还一味地找借口来掩饰
and now he's trying like hell to cover his ass.
你老板应该闭嘴
Your guy needs to shut up.
-怎么了?  -伤口裂开了
- what happened? - The patch must have blown.
呼叫艾迪森  让她来手术室
Page Addison. Tell her to meet me in the O. R. Let's--
我刚打电话给她父母报了平安了
I just called her parents. I told 'em everything was okay.
谢博德医生  我不明白
Hey, Dr. Shepherd--look, I don't understand.
他说手术很成功
He said that the surgery was a success.
我知道  我现在要过去了 有消息我会立刻通知你好吗
Okay, I'm gonna come out and give you an update as soon as we can, okay?
肿块没有消除
the swelling's not going down.
可能是脑室堵塞了
maybe the ventriculostomy is plugged.
不是
No.
该死
Damn it.
德里克?
Derek?
我得把颞叶取出来
I have to take out the temporal lobe.
这样她会死吗
Won't that kill her?
不会  但可能会丧失说话的能力
No, um, but she could lose some of her speech, uh...
发不出声  还有丧失记忆
voice, memory.
大脑会重建的
The brain can rewire.
以前为了停止抽搐我也这么做过
I've done it before to stop seizures.
你以前因为这个原因做过吗
have you done it before for this?
现在是第一次
I'm doing it now.
胎儿的心率又慢了
Baby's got decels again.
我们该怎么做  德里克?
What are we doing here, Derek?
刺刀钳
bayonet forceps.
我们该怎么跟那个男人说?
What are we supposed to say to this guy?
谢博德医生把你太太的脑子切掉一块
"Dr. Shepherd's cutting out parts of your wife's brain
但是我们希望她能度过难关?
But we're hopeful she'll pull through?
不  我们实话实说
No, we're gonna tell him the truth.
我们就说谢博德医生尽力
We're gonna say that Dr. Shepherd is doing everything
挽救你太太和孩子
He can to save your wife and child.
他的人生就要毁了
This guy's life ended as he knew it. Let's tell him that.
艾历克斯  别太...
- Alex, just be...
孩子的心率波动  但是
The baby's having some heart fluctuations, but
蒙哥马利医生正在尽力阻止早产
Dr. Montgomery is taking every precaution to avoid an early delivery.
我太太怎样了?
And my wife?
谢博德医生正在尽力止血
Dr. Shepherd is trying to get he bleeding under control,
但手术完成之前什么都不能确定
but we really won't know more until the surgery is finished.
她不会死吧?
But she won't die?
告诉我她不会死
Please tell me she won't die.
谢博德医生正竭尽所能保住你太太的生命
Dr. Shepherd is doing everything he can to make sure your wife lives.
- 她会活下来?  - 谢博德医生会竭尽全力的
- She'll live?  - Dr. Shepherd is doing absolutely everything he can.
我们该回去了
We should get back.
当然  呃  谢谢你们
Right. Of course. Yeah. Uh, thanks.
谢谢  你俩坏透了
- thank you.  - your guy sucks.
理查德先生
Mr. Richard
检查报告表明坎贝尔医生对您的诊断是错的
Your scan show a change from Dr. Campbell's original assessment.
手术时出现了并发症
There was a complication from the surgery
输胆管和动脉破裂
A lacerated bile duct and artery.
你需要再做个手术来进行修复
You'll need another surgery to repair it.
仅此而已
Is that all?
是的  仅此而已
Yes, that's all.
噢  谢天谢地
oh, thank god.
当听说外科主任亲自过来的时候
I-I thought when they told me the ch-- the chief of surgery was coming in
我以为自己死定了
I was a goner for sure.
我们想让您知道
we simply wanted to make you aware
您有权更换主刀医生
That it's within your rights to request a change of surgeon.
坎贝尔医生没空吗
Uh, Dr. Campbell's not available?
她有空
She's available.
那就不用换了  谢谢
Oh, then no, thank you.
我还是选坎贝尔医生
I-I-I choose Dr. Campbell.
很好
Very well.
坎贝尔医生
Dr. Campbell.
理查德
Richard.
主任  无心冒犯
Sir? Sir, with all due respect
我觉得病人好像没搞清
I don't think the patient's entirely clear on what happened.
你听见他怎么说了  杨医生
You heard the patient, Dr. Yang.
他不想换医生  但是主任  她...
- He wants his doctor. - But, sir, she--
放手吧  杨
back down, Yang.
求你了  我只想知道这样说贝利医生对吗
Come on. I just need you to tell me if it's worthy of Dr. bailey.
贝利医生是混蛋  就这么说
Dr. bailey is an ass. Say that.
就说她不理会住院医生
Say that she doesn't listen to the residents
对实习生重要情况的汇报
when they have important information about the interns.
你好像不明白推荐信的目的
I think you're missing the point of the exercise
应该说些溢美之词
which is to say nice and impressive things.
你还来这儿?
You still hang out here?
乔治  就说她可靠无私
George, just... say she's dependable, say she's selfless.
说她乐于奉献
Everything she was until she wasn't.
就说... 你该走了
Just... you should probably go.
可靠无私
Dependably selfless.
谢谢
Thank you.
伊兹贝尔 斯蒂文斯?
Isobel Stevens?
你很久没进我的手术室了  主任
It's been years since I've had you in my O. R. , Chief.
我还依稀记得那次你把钳子掉在病人体内
I seem to remember an incident with a clamp being dropped into an open body cavity.
你非要旧事重提吗
You're never gonna let me live that one down, huh?
严师出高徒
A good teacher never lets up on her students.
但我经常怀疑如今的教学方式
Although I've often wondered how the upcoming classes
怎么能让学生学到东西
learn anything with the way we teach these days.
主治医生只会一味地鼓励学生
Attendings seem more concerned with inspiring their students,
鼓励他们  肯定他们
using encouragement and validation and so forth,
而不是恐吓和羞辱他们
instead of instilling them with the fear and shame that actually
这样他们怎么能记住东西呢
causes one to remember anything in the first place.
亨特医生  你从部队里来
Dr. Hunt, you come from the military.
你能说是严酷的训练
Wouldn't you say the more rigid aspects of your training
造就了今时今日的你呢?
helped you become the doctor you are today?
当然  绝对没错
Yes, ma'am. Very much so.
但杨医生就另当别论了
Dr. Yang, on the other hand, well,
有些事教会我恐惧不常手术室里出现
something tells me fear is not something you've often faced in the O. R.
我要感激一切可以学习的机会
I'd appreciate any opportunity to learn.
那很好
Wonderful.
开始吧  告诉我如何处理肺栓塞
Let us begin then. Tell me how you do a pulmonary emboleomy.
我会从腿动脉插入一根可操纵导管
I'd insert a steerable catheter into the femoral vein
然后将荧光镜安到栓塞处
then position the fluoroscope adjacent to the embolus.
如果突然停电了你会怎么做
What would you do if the power should suddenly go out?
或者你在一家没钱买荧光镜的医院里呢?
Or if you had to operate in a hospital that couldn't afford a fluoroscope?
听着  这就像计算器
Look, it's like a calculator
你以为有了计算器
Do you think just because there's a machine to do it for them,
孩子们就可以不学加减乘除了
children shouldn't have to learn simple arithmetic?
机器能避免他们犯这种错误
if it will help them avoid mistakes like this one.
滚出我的手术室  出去!
Out... of my O. R. I said get out. Out!
这依然是我的手术室!
This is still my O. R. !
血流到额叶去了
She's bleeding into the frontal lobe.
如果现在我们能止血
Now if I can just stop the bleed
保住大脑的其余部分
save the rest of the brain
她还有的活
she'd have a chance.
心率更慢了
decels are getting longer.
德里克  我必须取出胎儿了
Derek, I have to deliver the baby.
不行  她... 她失血太多了  我能救她的
No, she--just... she's lost too much blood.
如果你现在给她开刀  她会大出血
If you cut her now, she'll bleed out. I can save her.
怎么救?
How?
我要切除她的额叶
I have to cut out the frontal lobe.
什么?
What?
德里克  别  住手  德里克
D-derek, no. Stop, Derek.
你够了
You've done enough.
切掉额叶?
her frontal lobe?
没有额叶和颞叶叫她怎么活啊?
Can she live without her frontal lobe and her temporal lobe?
她能活  德里克  不可能的
- Yes. - No, Derek, she can't.
听我说  胎儿已经缺氧了
Listen to me. This baby is not getting any oxygen now.
我知道你想救珍
I know that you want to save Jen.
我知道你觉得必须救  但不是用这种方法
I knowyou feel like you have to, but not this way.
我可以  我能救活他俩  她会活下来的
I can do this. I can save them both. She will live.
即使她活下来  也不是老公和孩子期待的那样
Not as the person that her husband and child need her to be.
她会丧失一切人类的基本功能
She'll lose everything about her that makes her human.
梅丽狄斯
Meredith.
你确定你可以吗
Are you sure you can do this?
我没得选  双极刀
I have no choice. Bipolars.
胎儿的心率过低
The baby's heart rate is bottoming out.
该死  德里克
Damn it, derek.
好吧  该死  我们等得太久了
Okay, damn it. We've gone--this has gone too far.
切除了前额叶  即使她能活下来
Taking the frontal lobe out, even if she does live
也是个怪物
you are creating a monster.
你不是救世主  德里克
You don't get to play god here, Dirlik.
珍已经死了  可是孩子还有机会存活
Jen is gone, but this baby has a chance to live.
让她走吧  放手吧
You need to let her go. Let it go.
求你...
Please let...
我要把孩子取出来了
I'm taking the baby out.
放下手术刀  艾迪森
Put down the scalpel, Addison!
你才该放下手术刀
you put down the scalpel.
艾迪森  放下手术刀
Addison, put the scalpel down.
你放下  让她去吧
You put the scalpel down! You have to let her go.
把你的手术刀放下  艾迪森
Take your hand off the scalpel, Addison!
-你放下... -放下
You take your-- take it off!
-梅丽狄斯  去叫主任  -哪都不许去
- Meredith, go get the chief. - Do not go anywhere.
克莱夫  快去
karev, go!
德里克  别这样
Derek, don't do this.
艾迪森  不许碰我的病人
Do not touch my patient, Addison.
梅丽狄斯
meredith...
德里克  看着我
Derek, look at me.
你没必要这么做
You don't have to do this.
珍已经死了  太晚了
Jen's gone. It's too late.
你救不了她
You can't save her.
她已经死了
She's gone.
我们可以救活孩子
We can save the baby.
德里克  看着我
Derek... look at me.
某些手术让最好的医生也手足无措
certain surgeries get the best of all of us.
我犯了错  一个大疏忽
I made a mistake, a careless mistake...
对此我很抱歉
and for that, I am sorry.
可我只是个普通人  作为一个普通人
But I am only human--as human as any of us--
为此
and for that...
我没什么觉得抱歉的
I do not apologize.
-玛格利特  你不必... -别再说了
- Margaret, you don't ha to-- no need to discuss it further, richard.
根本没必要
No need at all.
主任  去一号手术室
Chief, we need you in O. R. One.
-克莱夫  -事情紧急  主任
- Karev--right now, sir!
我是被军队... 开除的
I was fired... from the army.
他们称之为光荣退伍  可是...
They call it an honorable discharge, but...
服役期还没满  就要我走
they knew it was my time even though I didn'T.
为此我很感激
I'm grateful to them for that.
胎儿持续缺氧  我得把他取出来
the baby's still in distress. I need to take it out.
等等  再等一下
Wait. Just wait.
血可以止住
The bleeding could stop.
胎儿也会稳定下来的
The baby could stabilize.
如果你现在剖腹  她会失血过多而死
If you do a c-section now, she'll lose too much blood and she'll die.
-她已经死了 德里克  -请你再等一下
- She is dead, Derek  - Please just wait.
大部分脑组织死亡  从各种角度来讲  她已经死了
Most of her brain is gone. For all intents and purposes, she's dead.
克莱夫  呼叫空闲的医生手术组
karev, page Dr. Freedman's team.
告诉他们  我们有一个早产儿
Tell them we have a preemie on the way.
不要切
stop cutting!
为什么要这样
why are you cutting?!
梅丽狄斯  多拿点血过来
Meredith, get some more blood.
她需要更多的血
She needs more blood.
再拿些血来
Get some more blood.
要更多的血
We need more blood.
德里克  没用的
No more blood, Derek.
没用的
no more blood.
你来检查是很明智的  可是我没发现什么异常
You're smart to get it looked at, but it doesn't look too suspicious to me.
伴有乳酸脱氢酶高也不算吗
Even combined with high L. D. H. Levels?
升高的原因有很多  单细胞增多  锻炼也有可能
Oh... that could be caused by anything-- mono, exercise even.
再有神经障碍呢  还出现幻觉
coupled with neurological episodes, hallucinations?
检查完了
There we go. All done.
我们经常见到病人这样
You and I both see patients do this every day.
他们发现异常  就怀疑自己生病
They find something suspicious and convince themselves they're sick.
可作为医生  我们都知道  我们的职责就是让他们放心
But as doctors, you and I both know that it's our job to remain worry free
除非有确切的证据  那就是另外一回事了
until we have actual medical proof that says otherwise.
所以  你应该放松
So that's what you should do--relax.
明天这个时候  你会觉得自己的担忧
By this time tomorrow, you'll be laughing at the fact
是那么好笑
you thought there was anything wrong in the first place.
好  准备
Okay. Ready.
很健康
He looks strong.
好的  他一定能活下来
Okay. He definitely has a chance.
好吧  他把放进保温箱  我们把胎盘取出来
All right, let's get him intubated. Let's get the placenta.
给你妻子使用的激素促进了胎儿的肺部发育成熟
the steroids we gave your wife allowed your baby's lungs to mature.
谢博德医生连续三天的努力
That combined with the three extra days
让我们相信  你的孩子一定能活下来
that Dr. Shepherd took to do the surgery makes us very hopeful that he'll survive.
我不明白
I don't understand.
她就这么死了
She just died?
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道  你说过
Yeah, I know. You said that.
我在问她是怎么死的
Um... I'm asking how she died.
我们认为你妻子的血压太高导致血管不支
we believe your wife's high blood pressure is what caused the bypass to fail.
导致了颅内出血和肿胀
That caused the bleeding and the swelling in the brain.
谢博德医生尽了一切努力救她
Dr. Shepherd did everything he could to save her.
她的大脑损伤太严重了
There was too much damage to her brain.
蒙哥马利医生就着手把孩子取出来
That's when Dr. Montgomery stepped in to deliver the baby.
你说这只是个常规手术  她会没事的
You said it was a routine procedure but that she would be fine.
之后出现了并发症  你说你能治好
Then there was a complication... and you said you fixed that.
之后孩子又病了  这让珍再一次病倒
but then the baby got sick, and that made jen sick
你又说你可以治好她
But then you said that you fixed that, too.
现在呢  她死了
And now she's dead?
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
别对我说抱歉
Stop saying you're sorry.
你杀了她
You killed her.
你是凶手  杀人凶手
You're a murderer... a murderer.
把我的妻子还给我
Where's my wife?
我要我妻子  我的妻子
I want my wife. I want my wife.
我要我的...
I want my...
我...
I-I want...
我知道写的不好  可我尽力了
I know it's bad, but i'm tried
你很复杂  难以用语言形容
you just very complex and word defying
主任
chief
这才叫推荐信
that is a letter of recommendations
欧麦利  你想让我写成他这个样子
O'malley?You want me to take pointers from o'malley?
想写成其他样子也不太容易啊
You'd be hard-pressed to find a better person to take pointers from.
主... 主任
C-chief. Chief.
没错
Exactly.
我是外科主任
I am the chief of surgery.
我没时间写满足你虚荣的推荐信
And I don't have time to write letters to pump your ego.
我的脑外科主任被叫做杀人犯
My head of neuro is being called a murderer,
我不得不解雇我最老的普外医生  因为她不想退休
I have to fire my longest-standing general surgeon because she won't retire,
你诊所里的实习生又把血样弄错
interns are mixing up blood samples in your clinic,
而你却想让我花时间写推荐信  这样就能离开我了
and you want me to spend my time writing a recommendation so you can leave me?
离开你
Leave you?
主任  我是要申请儿科研究基金
Sir, I'M... applying for a fellowship in pediatric surgery.
我们先前不是这样说的
which is not what we had discussed.
你知道你浪费了我多少时间吗
Do you know how much of my time you wasted?
知道我下了多大代价来栽培你吗
Do you know the amount of work it takes to groom someone?
你本该接我的班的
You were supposed to become the next me.
你想让我接你的班
You wanted me to become the next you.
我又不是你的孩子
Now I'm not your son or your daughter.
你不能把你的希望和梦想寄托在我身上
You don't get to pin all your hopes and dreams on me, sir.
我在跟莱克茜交往
I'm seeing lexie.
还跟她上床了  可不只是这样
Well, I'm sleeping with her, too, but it's more than that.
我们很幸福
We're happy.
我很幸福
I'm happy.
好吧  这算是我自找的
okay, that's... maybe I deserve that.
你知道吗  凭什么打我
No, you know what?I didn't deserve that.
你没权管我跟谁上床
You have no right to tell me who I can sleep with--oh!
你关心的是继承人的问题
you're worried about your legacy.
我不是你的继承人  而且申请儿科不是...
But I am not your legacy, and me applying  peds is not--
你没在听我说  主任
you are not listening to me, sir.
什么...
What the...
够了  够了  住手
Come on. Come on. Stop.
好了  住手
come on, stop.
这就是她男人
That's her guy.
我会做肺部动脉切开术
I would do a pulmonary arteriotomy--
直视血块  用无损伤镊子直接夹出来
directly visualize the clot and use atraumatic forceps to extract it.
没有荧光镜  我就会这样做肺部动脉切开术
That's how I would do a pulmonary embolectomy without a fluoroscope.
你专程来告诉我答案  说明你将会是个
The fact that you felt the need to come and tell me
出色的外科医生
that you're a much better surgeon than I first thought.
我决定了  今天是我最后一次做手术
I've decided today's surgery was my last.
你看我的眼神好像在说  不用很久
You look at me like you won't wake up one day not that far from now--
非常快  你将会成为另一个我
so much faster than you can imagine-- and find that you are me.
当你不再动刀的时候  还剩下些什么
When you can't cut anymore, what will you have?
我曾是上帝
I was a god...
在这间手术室  拿着手术刀  我是上帝
in this O. R. Holding a scalpel... I was a god.
现在
And now...
你会是怎么样的呢
what will you have?
看起来还挺太平吗
I don't see anyone burning the place down.
他们就这样  本来一切正常
That's how they do it-- do everything right,
你一不注意  就有大麻烦了
and as soon as you look away, they screw it all up.
很抱歉  我今天一直在忙自己的事情
Hey, uh, I'm sorry I was busy earlier with myself.
我太忙了  对不起
I was busy, so I'm sorry.
没关系
Don't be.
我还骂你混蛋来着  你是对的
I called you an ass, so... and you were right.
我需要放松一下
I think I just needed to vent.
我... 厌倦了这个地方
I... I'm sick of this place.
是啊  我刚看到德里克 谢博德因为厌倦了这个地方  动手打人
Hell, I just watched Derek shepperred beat up a man 'cause he's sick of it.
事情就是这样
That's the way it works.
失去的病人  犯的错  让我们收获很多
The patients we lose, the mistakes we make-- that's how we learn.
这是必须要面对的事情
That's the only way it's ever been done.
伊兹 斯蒂文斯  要是你能找到更好的方法
Figure out a better way, and you, izzie stevens,
会成为比我们更好的医生
will be a better doctor than the rest of us.
病人把我们当做救世主
Patients see us as gods...
伊兹
izzie.
或视我们如恶魔
Or they see us as monsters.
事实上  我们只是普通人
But the fact is, we're just people.
好了  没有骨折  最好给他冰敷
Okay, well, it's not broken, but you should ice it.
很多的冰  再见
Lots and lots of ice, Goodbye.
真对不起
I'm so sorry.
值了
It was worth it.
不  不值得这样
No. It--it--it wasn't
也许有那么一点值
maybe a little.
谢谢
thank you.
我们也会捅娄子
We screw up...
也会迷失
we lose our way.
我想给你点经验教训... calliope
I have experience to give... calliope.
生活经验  我结过婚
Life experience, like the fact that I was married.
你知道吗
Did you know that?
还有  我参加过和平队  去博兹瓦纳
Or that I was in the peace corps?Botswana.
这让我立志学医
That's what convinced me to go to med school.
最近  我... 爱上了做饭
And most recently, I've, uh, experienced the joy of cooking.
是的  我做的香溜鸡片无人能及
Yeah. I make an excellent chicken piccata
还有很多好吃的菜
in addition to many other delicious meals
你很走运   能尝到我的手艺
that you'd be very lucky to experience yourself.
你完全无视这些  说明你阅历不足
And the fact that you can't open your eyes to see that makes you inexperienced.
卡里欧琵  这是朱莉
calliope, this is julie...
我正约会呢
my date.
最好的医生也要休息
Even the best of us  have our off days.
推荐信
Letter of recommendation.
凯丽告诉我主任写推荐信的事了
Callie told me about the chief's letter.
我想这是我回洛杉矶之前唯一能做的事了
I figured it's the least I can do before I get on a plane back to L. A.
艾迪森 蒙哥马利 谢-谢-你！
Addison montgomery, thank you.
不用客气  好好干吧
No need to thank me. Just, you know, kick ass.
别让我后悔写了"你是最有前途的年轻儿科医生"
Don't make me regret writing that you're the most promising young peds surgeon
"能与你共事是我的荣幸"
I've ever had the pleasure of working with.
不过  我们还是会继续前行
Still, we move forward.
今天  你... 你教训了那个该教训的人
today you were-- you were a teacher to someone who needed to learn,
可是你也欺负了需要同情的前辈
but you were also a bully to someone who needed compassion.
你两者兼备
You were both.
好吧  为什么不能兼备
Well-- why can't I be?
我不是恃强凌弱  而且  我是对的
I wasn't a bully and... I was right.
好吧
Right.
你知道  你跟她很像
You know, you're a lot like her
顽固不化  固执己见  又绝顶聪明
Stubborn, opinionated... Smart.
四十年之内  想从你手里抢走手术刀绝非易事
40 years from now, I'm gonna have to pry that scalpel out of your hand, too.
我死了  你就有希望了
From my cold, dead hands.
你没听明白
you're missing the point.
我想跟你在一起  从现在开始  四十年
I want to be around 40 years from now.
我们不仰仗荣誉  也不会为我们所拯救过的生命庆祝
We don't rest on our laurels  or celebrate the lives  we've saved in the past.
上帝啊
oh... oh, god.
因为总有病人需要我们的帮助
because there's always  some other patient  that needs our help.
我们要强迫自己不断努力  不断学习...
So we force ourselves  to keep trying, to keep learning...
你们动机不明  粗心大意  自私自利
you're unmotivated, you're careless, selfish,
不专心  这医院里相当多的人  我不愿把生命托付给他们
distracted and pretty much the people in this hospital I would least trust with my life.
可事情就是这样
But that's the way it's supposed to be.
你们是实习生  是孩子
You're interns. You're babies.
能在这里工作是你们的荣幸
And you're all lucky to work here.
因为能救人一命  我们都很幸运
We're all lucky because we get to save lives.
每一天  我们都要救死扶伤
Every day, we get to save lives.
我们的职责就是如此
That's what we do. That's our job, and...
不是所有的人都能胜任这工作  所以...
it's not something a lot of people get to do, so...
-总是希望... -开始吧
- in the hope that... - let's begin.
也许
Maybe.
新的游戏
New game.
-某一天  -这是X病人
- Someday... - this is patient "X.
29岁  女性  最初我们误诊为贫血
" She's a 29-year-old female we misdiagnosed wi anemia the first time she came to us.
这次不要在犯错了
Let's not make the same mistake again.
我们只能离病人期望的"上帝"更近一点
We'll come  just a little bit closer to the gods our patients  need us to be.